Efren CastroFull Stack Web Developer



Summary

Web Developer residing in **Denver, Colorado** with over 8 years of programming experience. Currently specializing in developing performant, organized, and scalable API applications.

Contact

Phone: (720)539-6101

Email: efrencastro.dev@gmail.com Portfolio: https://amazingefren.com

LinkedIn: /in/amazingefren Github: amazingefren

Techincal Skills

Web Development

 Typescript, Javascript, React, Vue.js, HTML5, CSS / SASS

API Development

 Express, Fastify, NodeJS, GraphQL, Authentication, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL

Languages

- Python, Lua, Rust, Go, C, C++

Markup / Scripting

- Markdown, LaTeX, Bash

Deployment

 Nginx, CRON, Vim, Ubuntu, Git, TravisCl, CircleCl, SSH, Process Management, Automation and many more linux sysadmin tasks

Interests and Hobbies

Linux (Neo)Vim

Machine Learning
Software Engineering

Steam Proton Development

3D Blender WebGL

GIMP

Extra Film and Photography

Cyber Security

Projects

· Sosile Client

Sosile is a social media site that I am actively developing as a platform to experiment with a larger set of technologies such as WebRTC. Built with NextJS,Apollo,Typescript

Code: https://git.amazingefren.com/sosile-client

Live: https://sosile.amazingefren.com

· Sosile Server

API featuring a fully modularized GraphQL endpoint utilizing awesome technologies such as NestJS, PostgreSQL, Fastify, PrismaORM, and protected with a OAuth2.0 inspired Authentication model

Code: https://git.amazingefren.com/sosile-server

Live: https://sosile.amazingefren.com

Experience

Web Developer - Contract-Hire

June 2020 - November 2020
 Developed a REST API with Typescript implementing Square Orders API and Postmates providing seamless mobile-ordering for the people impacted during the COVID-19 pandemic

January 2021 - March 2021
 Deployment of a Jitsi Meet Server on a fully featured Nginx reverse proxy.

 Developed a set automation scripts implementing Bash, Python, Docker

Certifications

- Harvard University 2020
 Computer Science Certification
 Focus on Software Engineering
- University of Denver 2019
 Coding Certification
 Focus on Full Stack Web Development

Education

- University of Colorado Boulder
 Studies in Computer Science
 Completed Coursework from 2017-2018
- Community College of Aurora
 General Studies
 Completed Coursework from 2016-2017